## ISHU KUMAR

### CONTACT

Email: ishurps@gmail.com Phone: +91 7892499769

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lshukumar1

### CAREER OBJECTIVE

2+ years of experience as a Java/J2EE Developer in analysis, design, implementation, integration, testing and maintenance of applications. Worked on multiple Industrial Java development project. Now looking forward to utilize expertise and understanding of all aspects of Java development to continue professional development.

### **EDUCATION**

New Horizon College of Engineering, Bangalore

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Science and Engineering)

Aug 2020 9.19/10 CGPA

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Capgemini Technology Services India Limited | Bangalore Senior Analyst (Feb 2021 – present)

JLP

- Use Java/J2EE technologies to develop web applications for client server environments and add functionalities to existing applications.
- Revamp various Java applications developed with Spring Boot and older J2EE.
- Conduct user requirements analysis to design and program application and deliver support for system enhancement.
- Playing pivot role as a part of an agile scrum team accountable, developing new applications using spring framework.
- Consult with customers on project status and technical concerns.

## **Analyst** (Sep 2020 – Feb 2021)

Online Term Insurance

- Working on Agile Scrum methodology and involving in stand-up meetings to monitor the progress.
- Involving in requirements gathering, analysis, design, and documentation of the application.
- Implementing Java components using Spring MVC, Spring Security Modules.
- Developing microservices using Java Spring Boot, Hibernate, RESTful services with good quality of code.
- Configured Spring to route to the respective databases to fetch data.
- Built front end application with JS Frameworks (React JS) and connected with backend.

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Improved Billing System (Feb 2020 – May 2020)

- Tools Java and Python as programming languages and MySQL for database
- Description Application to make billing system paperless and reduce overall hardware in shops.

### **CERTIFIED COURSES**

- Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python (IBM, Sep 2021)
- Python for Data Science, AI & Development (IBM, Aug 2021)
- Google Data Analytics (Google, July 2021)
- Java, J2EE and SOA Certification Training (Edureka, Apr 2018)

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java
- Python
- Machine Learning
- Microservices
- Scikit-learn
- MySQL, SQL
- MongoDB
- Regression
- Supervised learning
- Unsupervised learning
- Data Analytics
- REST API
- Spring Boot
- Visualization
- Cloud GCP, AWS
- ReactJS